何だ
走って
いや
韻子
緊急発進
そうか
援護します
スレイン様
それが…
ここは…
中も同じです
そうなるのか
待避
暗殺部隊か
アセイラム姫は？
まだ連絡ないよ
作戦終了
アセイラム姫殿下です
格納庫で交戦中です
韻子　拾ってくれ
姫…様
敵襲　敵襲
地球人どもを排除しろ
危険です　外は戦闘中です
最大戦速　戦闘宙域を急速離脱
僕の意向を　忖度すれば
脱出　できなかったのか
嘘をついた？　セラムさんを逃がすために
理屈の海だけの　解を遊べば
降下した言葉・嘘・キマグレ
ほどいては溢れた　お互いのナミダ
君の手が広げた　何もない空よ
soul・art　リズムを奏でて
合図をリングに繋ぐ
形だけのシステムと
Where am I?
形見だけの呪いも
I see.
逃亡人の恥じらい音
想像Drive　CarryOn　意地なTIRE
You lied to make her run away?
誤解あるドアに　ゼロが眠りかけた
I see.
It was an accurate conjecture of my plan.
時計抱いた人と天使
永久に飽くドール達
Sir Slaine.
また同じ風邪に　モガいて
What is it?
There is an altercation in the hangar.
Their assassination squad?
No.
It is Princess Asseylum.
申し訳ありません　クランカイン伯爵
I will provide cover.
巻き込んでしまって
いいえ　これも私の任務ですから
Run!
任務？
はい　私は皇帝陛下の命によって　ここに参ったのです
Eliminate the Terrans!
We're under attack!
お爺様の？
レイレガリア皇帝陛下は
先代ザーツバルム伯爵死後の地球圏統治に　疑問を持たれました
Perform emergency launch.
It wouldn't be safe, sir.
There's a battle raging outside.
It's no safer in here.
Get us away from the combat zone
at maximum speed.
そして私に　その調査とともに　姫の安否を確かめるよう命じたのです
Retreat!
では　お爺様と連絡が取れれば…
連絡を取ることは可能です
しかし…
クランカイン伯爵　月面基地より通信です
Your Highness...
つないでください
Inko...
クランカイン卿　アセイラム姫をどこへ連れていかれるのですか
Where is Princess Asseylum?
She hasn't contacted me yet.
これはトロイヤード卿
Is she still inside?
姫を危機から保護し　避難するところです
No...
月面基地は強固な要塞　ここをおいてほかに安全な場所などありません
しかし戦闘状態にありました
Mission successful.
ご安心を　すでに基地の敵は排除しました
Inko, come pick me up.
早くお戻りください
いいえ　私は戻りません
I'm truly sorry, Count Klancain.
私は…
I had no wish to involve you in this.
Do not worry.
地球で鳥を見ました
This is part of my mission too.
姫様
Mission?
地球は回復し　人と自然とが共存していました
Yes.
I am here under His Imperial Majesty's orders.
My grandfather's?
あなたは教えてくれましたよね
Emperor Rayregalia was doubtful of the campaign staged by the previous Count Saazbaum.
人と自然は…
地球とヴァースは…
ともに栄えることができると
He commanded me to investigate and see to your safety.
はい　その通りです
確かにそのように申しました
Then I must speak with my grandfather!
ステイギス隊を追跡に向かわせました
I can establish contact.
捕捉次第　拿捕しろ
お願いです　スレイン
However...
どうか戦争をやめてください
Count Klancain, we have a transmission from the moon base.
そして　地球と和平を結んでください
Put it onscreen.
そうですね　分かりました
Count Klancain, where do you mean to take Princess Asseylum?
そのことについて話しましょう
Ah, Count Troyard.
I am presently evacuating Her Highness to protect her from our enemies.
スレイン
The moon base is heavily fortified.
その宙域は危険です　早くお戻りを
There is no place safer.
クランカイン伯爵　すぐに引き返してください
I seem to recall a battle raging within it.
承りかねます
Have no fear.
私は　アセイラム姫の命に従います
All enemy forces have been eradicated.
ステルス機能　最大
Please return at once.
No!
了解
I will not return!
航宙船ハドリアクス　船影が消失しました
I...
捜索を続けろ
watched birds on Earth.
はっ
これで　ひとまず追手の心配は要りません
Your Highness...
The Earth was recovering,
and mankind was coexisting with nature.
ありがとうございます
しかし　これからどうすれば
You were the one who taught me that.
That mankind and nature...
地球の軍は私を狙っています
That Earth and Vers...
軌道騎士たちも　スレインの指示を
could prosper together!
Yes.
何とかデューカリオンの皆さんと連絡を取ることは
It is as you say.
I said exactly that.
姫様
姫様に味方される騎士の方が
I've dispatched Stygis Platoon in pursuit.
Have them seize the ship.
界塚伊奈帆のメッセージを届けてくださった…
I beg you, Slaine.
Please stop this war!
Make peace with Earth.
マズゥールカ伯爵です
今こそアセイラム姫殿下に我が忠義を示す時
Yes.
Perhaps you are right.
揚陸城　離陸
Let us speak about that.
Slaine...
The sector you are entering is dangerous.
You should return immediately.
Count Klancain, please turn back at once.
I am afraid I cannot comply.
I shall observe Princess Asseylum's orders.
Maximum power to stealth devices!
Yes, sir.
クライスデールリーダーより各機
The spacecraft Hadriacus
has vanished from our sensors.
右舷前方の敵を狙え
デューカリオンに近寄らせるな
Keep looking.
3時の方向　仰角60
Yes, sir.
敵編隊が接近
That should get him off our backs for the time being.
右舷　対空砲火を強化
本部より入電　撤退命令っす
Thank you.
撤退？
But what should I do now?
どうやら結果が出たみたいですね
結果？
我々を囮に使った本命の作戦です
Earth's military is trying to kill me,
and the Orbital Knights obey Slaine.
撤退準備
全機に帰還命令
マスタング00　11　接近中です
Is there any way I could make contact with the Deucalion?
帰投コース
韻子と伊奈帆君だ
Your Highness...
着艦を許可する　収容急げ
There is still one who is on your side.
The knight who delivered the message from Kaizuka Inaho.
Count Mazuurek.
Now is the time to demonstrate
my loyalty to Princess Asseylum.
Landing Castle, lift off!
敵わぬと見て逃げるか
どういうつもりだ
トロイヤード伯爵　連合軍が撤退します
追撃しますか
いや　全機帰還せよ
Clydesdale Leader to all units!
次の攻撃に備えて補給だ
Target the enemies off starboard!
それと　揚陸城を呼べ
Don't let them get close to the Deucalion!
月面基地の防衛に回せ
Enemies approaching from
three o'clock, sixty degrees up!
了解
Focus AA fire to starboard.
Orders from HQ!
We're to withdraw!
Withdraw?
それはお姉様のものですか
Looks like they got what they came for.
What they came for?
レムリナ姫
Whatever main operation we were used to divert attention from.
お姉様は？
Prepare to withdraw.
そう　またお会いできるかしら
All units are to return.
Mustang 00 and 11 are approaching.
はい　必ず
They're coming back!
Inko and Inaho!
可哀想
They're cleared to land.
Recover them at once.
あの人も
あなたも
伊奈帆
界塚少尉の容態は？
命に別状はありません
それよりも　アナリティカルエンジンが脳神経に負担をかけています
だめだって言ったのに　領域をこんなに拡張して
They flee in the face of our superiority.
どういうことですか
What are they playing at?
脳の一部を機械に譲ってるんだ
まったく　無茶を
Count Troyard, Earth's forces are retreating.
Should we pursue?
No. Return to base.
Rearm and refuel for the next offensive.
何とかして　この戦争を止めなければ
Also, summon the Landing Castles.
Have them bolster the moon base's defenses.
私が軌道騎士の皆さんに呼びかけましょう
As you wish.
恐れながら　それだけでは難しいかと
なぜですか
もとより軌道騎士たちは地球と戦い　地球を占領することを望んでいます
Is that my sister's?
Princess Lemrina...
そこへトロイヤード伯爵は　王国の命令という免罪符を与えました
Did my sister...
新たな王国での地位と　アルドノアの起動権を保証して
I see.
I wonder if we will see her again.
I'm certain we will.
彼らを束ねたのです
I pity you.
アセイラム姫殿下　あなたとの婚約を切り札にして
You...
ただ停戦を呼びかけても　今は信用を失うだけでしょう
and her both.
あなたを騙る妹君が　彼の元にいる限り
Inaho...
What is his condition?
It's nothing life-threatening.
But I'm concerned with the strain the
analytical engine is putting on his cranial nerves.
これはアセイラム姫殿下　ご機嫌麗しゅう
力を貸していただき　ありがとうございます
I told him not to let it expand too much.
もったいないお言葉
What does that mean?
私のほうこそ　借りを返すことができてほっとしております
He's given up part of his brain to the machine.
借り？
Crazy kid.
はい
地球の少年　界塚伊奈帆に
I have to put a stop to this war.
隊の一部を月面基地に向けていたと聞くが
I will speak to all the Orbital Knights.
I'm afraid that alone may not be enough.
どういうつもりだね　マグバレッジ艦長
Why not?
現場での判断です
The Orbital Knights have long since desired to wage war with Earth and conquer it.
今姫殿下を失えば　和平のきっかけを永遠に失うことになります
Count Troyard has issued them
carte blanche with a royal decree.
何の話だ
敵の中核は本物のアセイラム姫ではありません
He has won them over to his side with promises of status and Aldnoah activation privileges
その情報は裏が取れていない
事実が変わるわけではありません
once he comes into his own kingdom.
Princess Asseylum, this all hinges on his upcoming marriage to you.
マズゥールカ城の打ち上げを確認した
マズゥールカ伯爵が逃亡した際
Calling for an end to hostilities will only invite their distrust at this point.
直前に君の兵が面会したと聞いているが
He still has your sister, who can pretend to be you.
その通りですが　何が
今回も君の兵が送られていた
奇遇だな　実に奇遇だ
Princess Asseylum.
I am overjoyed to see you unharmed.
間もなく　月と地球が最接近する
Thank you for coming to my assistance.
サテライトベルトに駐屯する揚陸城が月面基地の援軍に加わるだろう
You give me too much credit.
I am merely relieved to be able to repay my debt.
その前に決着をつけなければならない
Debt?
Yes.
新な作戦を伝える
My debt to the Terran boy...
全軍集結し　月面基地に総攻撃をかける
Kaizuka Inaho.
デューカリオンには先鋒を命ずる
了解
詳細は追って伝える　健闘を祈る
I've received report that you sent a team into the moon base.
Would you mind explaining why,
Captain Magbaredge?
嫌われましたね
It was a judgment call
based on the circumstances.
まさか
If we lose the princess now,
our only chance at peace is gone for good.
私の方が嫌ってるのです
スレインはどうして　このような戦争を
Why would Slaine instigate this war?
Your Highness...
姫様
The Slaine I knew was kind.
私の知っているスレインは
He loved nature and the Earth.
優しくて自然が好きで　地球を愛する人でした
He would never start a meaningless war.
決して　無益な戦争をするような人では
So why?
なのに　どうして…
Your Highness...
姫様
Sir Slaine hasn't changed one bit!
スレイン様は何も変わってはおりません
What?
I cannot judge if he is right or wrong.
スレイン様の行動の正否は　私には分かりません
でも　あの方はいつでも姫様のことを思ってらっしゃいました
But you were always foremost in his thoughts.
ご自分の立場や命が危うくなろうとも
He did everything for your sake,
caring not if it put his status or life in danger.
常に姫様のためを願っていました
Always believing
姫様が　目覚める日を…
that one day,
you would awaken...
ずっと信じて
Yes. I suppose that's true.
ええ　そうですね
あなたの言うとおりです　エデルリッゾ
You are right on that count, Eddelrittuo.
ヴァースに連絡を取ることはできますか
Are you able to make contact with Vers?
Yes.
はい
しかし　皇帝陛下は…
However, His Majesty...
We can no longer afford to hesitate.
もう　手段を選んでいる場合ではありません
クランカイン伯爵　あなたの力を貸してください
Count Klancain, please lend me your assistance.
I will use the Hadriacus' audience chamber.
ハドリアクスの謁見の間を使います
As you command, Princess Asseylum.
アセイラム姫殿下のお心のままに
Notice to all units:
各部隊に通達
Operation will begin at 1500 hours UTC as planned.
作戦は予定通り　UTC1500時に開始
Stand by at battle stations.
戦闘配置にて待機
鞠戸大尉　出撃ですか
Lieutenant Marito, are you deploying?
Yeah.
最後に先生と一杯やりたかったが
I was hoping to have one last drink with you, Doc,
but I guess I missed my chance.
機会がなかったな
らしくないですね
That's not like you.
まあ　低気圧下だ　悪酔いするとまずいしな
Well, we're in a low-pressure environment.
Wouldn't want it to affect me too badly.
そうじゃなくて
That's not what I meant.
There's no "last" about it.
最後じゃないでしょ
Yeah. We'll have that drink when I get back.
ああ　帰ったらな
Is this what you'd call a "final battle"?
これって　最終決戦ってやつですかね
I guess.
さあね　決着つくなら　そうじゃない？
If we beat 'em here,
there won't be another one, right?
戦死したら　そいつにはそん時が最終決戦だな
And if anyone dies in action,
that's as final a battle as they can get!
Stop it!
もう…
Could you not jinx us?
縁起でもないこと　言わないでください
Yeah! We're all gonna make it back in one piece!
そうですよ　みんな生きて帰るんですから
スレイン様　連合軍が集結を始めています
Sir Slaine.
Earth has begun to gather her forces.
What shall we do about them?
いかがなさいますか
No change of plan.
変更はない
全軍出撃し　連合軍を迎撃する
Launch all forces and intercept them.
Also, send a request for assistance
from our supporting Orbital Knights.
それと同時に　我々を支持する軌道騎士たちに協力を仰ぐ
Assistance?
協力？
地球全土に総攻撃をかける
We will launch an all-out offensive against the Earth.
They shall learn how it feels to no longer have anywhere to go home to.
帰る場所を失うというのがどういうことか　知るといい
なお君
Nao.
Yuki?
ユキ姉
Are you okay, Nao?
大丈夫？　なお君
Yeah.
うん
よかった
Thank goodness.
You did good today. Now rest up.
お疲れ様　しばらくは安静よ
He's going to launch an all-out attack.
総攻撃　するんだ
作戦時間は　もうすぐ
The operation should be beginning soon.
ちょっと　ダメよ　勝手に起きちゃう
Hey!
Stop! You need to stay in bed!
I'm sorry, Yuki.
ごめん　ユキ姉
やらないといけないことができたんだ
There's something I have to do.
なお君
Nao!
Please.
お願い　行かせて
Let me go.
ダメって言っても行くって顔してる
I can tell from your face
that you'll go no matter what I say.
ユキ姉も　言っても聞かないから仕方ないって声してるよ
And I can tell from your voice
that you're ready to give up and let me.
まったく
Seriously.
When you come back, let's have dinner together.
帰ったら　一緒に御飯食べよ
That's a death flag, you know.
それって　死亡フラグだよ
Hey, don't talk like that.
こら　そういうこと言わないの
You're definitely coming back alive.
絶対　生きて帰って来るんだから
Yeah. And so are you.
うん　ユキ姉も
Yo, Inaho.
よ　伊奈帆
体は　もういいのか
Out of bed already?
うん
Yeah.
これ…
Is this...
ああ　スレイプニール最終決戦仕様だ
You guessed it!
It's the Sleipnir final battle loadout!
でも　余計なペイロードじゃないか
Little too much junk in the trunk if you ask me, though.
宇宙戦でこれを使うほど接近するって　よっぽどだぜ
Getting close enough to use this
in a space battle would be crazy.
そのよっぽどになりそうなんだ
Well, this whole op's going to be crazy.
Seriously?
マジかよ
He's not taking this seriously at all!
全然マジなんかじゃない
韻子
Inko?
なんで男子ってみんなこうなわけ？
Why are boys always like this?
Inaho, you're in no condition to go into battle.
伊奈帆　そんな体で出撃なんて無理だよ
Let us handle this.
後は私たちに任せて
That I cannot do.
それはできない
What?!
What the hell?
何それ
You think you're some hotshot ace?
That you're special?
自分がエースだとか　特別だとか思ってるわけ？
I've never thought that.
そんなこと　一度も考えたことはないよ
Come on, Inaho!
ね　伊奈帆　なんで分からないふりするの
Why are you acting like you can't see it?
If you deploy now, you might die out there for real!
今出たら　本当に帰ってこれないかもしれないんだよ
もう　あの時みたいな奇跡は　起こらないんだよ
You pulled through last time,
but miracles don't come twice!
やだよ　また　あんな思いをするのは
I couldn't bear...
to go through that again.
自分だけ休んでるわけにはいかないよ
I can't just lie in bed while everyone else fights.
そうだぞ　韻子
He's right, Inko.
If you care for him, you'll let him go without a fight.
こういう場合　黙って見送るのも　優しさだぜ
We've got enough to worry about ourselves.
今は自分たちの心配してりゃいいんだよ
伊奈帆に比べりゃ　俺たちのほうが生存確率　多分低いし
If I had to say it, compared to Inaho,
our chances of survival are pretty low.
Get real! I'm an ace too!
冗談　私だってエースなんだから
ありがとう　韻子　カーム
Thanks, Inko.
Calm.
It's okay.
大丈夫　皆生きて帰るよ
We're all going to make it back alive.
僕の左目がそう言ってる
My left eye says so.
Master switch, on.
マスタースイッチオン
Fuel cells, heat up.
燃料電池ヒートアップ
Voltage, check.
電圧チェック
Pump activated.
ポンプ始動
Accumulator, pressure all good.
アキュムレータ圧力チェック
フォースフィードバックチェッキングプログラム　スタート
Force feedback checking program, start.
エジェクションシート正常
Ejection seat functional.
IFF confirmed.
IFF　確認
Tactical datalink activated.
戦術データリンク　アクティベート
Systems, all green.
システムオールグリーン
Mustang 00...
マスタング00　レディ
Ready.
Grandfather...
お爺様…
Grandfather.
お爺様
私です　アセイラムです
It's me.
Asseylum.
Do you recognize me?
お分かりになりますか
Ah... Asseylum...
おお　アセイラム
You look well.
お元気そうで
うん　大儀である
I am weary.
地球の制圧は進んでおるか
Is our conquest of Earth proceeding as planned?
I would ask you a favor in regards to that.
今日はそのことでお願いがあって参りました
地球と和平を結んで欲しいのです
I ask that you make peace with Earth.
軌道騎士たちに戦争をやめるよう　お爺様から命令してください
Please order the Orbital Knights to cease fighting.
それは　出来ぬ
I cannot.
Grandfather?
お爺様
地球は決して許さぬ
The Terrans can never be forgiven.
Press them with everything we have.
攻撃の手を緩めるな
Conquer them, and make them ours.
我らの支配下に治めよ
お爺様　どうして　地球を憎むのですか
Grandfather, why...
Why do you hate Earth so?
Where is Gillzeria?
ギルゼリアはどこだ
What has become of my son?
我が息子はどうした　早く地球を占領せよ
Conquer the Earth at once!
お父様は亡くなりました　ヘブンズ・フォールで
Father passed away during Heaven's Fall.
地球人め　よくも我が息子を
Wretched Terrans. How dare they kill my son?
Not even my granddaughter, Asseylum, was spared.
しかも　孫娘アセイラムまで
I'm right here.
私はここにおります
Vers.
ヴァースだ
古代文明人はこの星を　火星のことをそう呼んでいた
That is what those of the ancient civilization called this planet—Mars.
Grandfather...
お爺様
Rejoice.
喜べ
For I have discovered...
私は発見したぞ　火星の超科学を
a Martian superscience.
その名を　アルドノアという
Its name is Aldnoah.
This is wonderful.
素晴らしい　人類はさらなる躍進を遂げるだろ
Mankind can now make even greater progress.
Aldnoah will make everyone happy.
アルドノアは　人を幸せにする夢の技術だ
It is the technology of our dreams.
Yes.
はい
It is a great power.
大きな力だ
道を誤ることなく　大切に育てよ
It must not be misused.
Nurture it with care.
はい
I will.
そこにいるのは　アセイラムか
Is that you, Asseylum?
How you've grown.
大きくなったな
美しくなった
And how fair you've become.
Become a fine princess.
よい姫になれ
そして　人を幸福に導け
Lead our people to happiness.
はい
I will.
煌めく欠片　降り注ぐ空に
Klancain.
クランカイン
I will need all that your status and connections can achieve.
あなたの地位と人脈のすべてを私に預けていただきます
未来繋ぐ扉　隠した
Of course.
はい　喜んで
I would be honored.
忠誠　ありがとうございます
Your loyalty is appreciated, Count Cruhteo.
クルーテオ伯爵
本当は誰も皆　傷つくと恐れてる
Goddamn Martians!
この火星人どもが
ヴァースに　栄光あれ
Glory to Vers!
何かを守るため　壊すために　僕らは
What the hell is that?
何なんだ　あれは
Slice them to ribbons!
刻め
Harmonious
想いは　夜空を超えて
映し出す　それは光の道導
下僕たち　殲滅せよ
Annihilate them, my servants!
Open a comms channel
and contact all Orbital Knights!
回線を開け　すべての軌道騎士に通達する
悲しい決意は　雨が撫でるだろう
Yes, sir!
はっ
The moon base has begun its all-out offensive on the United Forces of Earth!
月面基地は地球連合軍の総力戦を開始した
サテライトベルト及び地上に降下した軌道騎士の諸兄よ
Hear me, Knights that have traveled down to the satellite belt and to the planet's surface.
赦し合う強さ　教えて欲しい
Launch an attack against the forces of Earth, wherever you are!
各々の地にて　連合軍に向け　一斉攻撃をせよ
地球人に今一度　我々の絶大な力を示すのだ
Prove to them our immense strength once and for all!
どうか　愛すること 忘れないで
そして連合軍に抵抗すること…
And show them that resistance—
ヴァース軌道騎士の皆さん
Hear me, Orbital Knights of Vers.
Princess Asseylum!
アセイラム姫
私はヴァース帝国第一皇女　アセイラム・ヴァース・アリューシアです
I am Asseylum Vers Allusia,
first princess of the Vers Empire.
たったひとつのきっかけから　争いが始まり
This great war began from a single confrontation.
とても大きな戦争に発展しました
What's going on?
これは…
海賊放送？
A pirate broadcast?
It's being transmitted on all bands.
全帯域で発信されています
Many different people with different ideals have clashed, bringing forth great tragedy.
様々な人の様々な思いがすれ違い
大きな不幸を生みました
And that is truly regrettable.
それは　とても悲しいことです
私はこの戦争を憂い
I too have suffered from this war.
I feel both shame and regret for our use of a power not meant for human hands.
人の手に余る大きな力の扱いについて反省と共に
深く後悔をしています
And so, here and now...
私は　今ここに
先代皇帝　レイレガリア・ヴァース・レイヴァースの跡を継ぎ
I claim my birthright to Rayregalia Vers Rayvers' title
ヴァース帝国の女王になります
and hereby name myself Empress of Vers.
I also announce my engagement to Count Cruhteo of the Orbital Knights' Thirty-Seven Clans.
そして　軌道騎士37家門の一人　クルーテオ伯爵を夫に迎えます
We of the Vers imperial family hereby
extend the olive branch of peace to Earth!
我々ヴァース帝国王室は　地球との和平を望みます
本字幕由诸神字幕组出品，仅供学习交流，禁止用于商业用途
更多中日双语字幕，尽在 i.kamigami.org 和微博 @诸神字幕组
日听:ikoko&Archer  翻译:mam&郝郝
校对:安少&zwx  时间轴:Foyzi  压制:河蟹
kirameku kakera
Somewhere in a sky
furisosogu sora ni
of burning fragments falling heavy
mirai tsunagu doa kakushita
I lost the gateway to the future
hontou wa daremo mina
Every one of us
kizu tsuku to osoreteru
is afraid of being wounded
nanika wo mamoru tame kowasu tame ni
It is our wish to destroy or protect
bokura wa harmonious
that makes us harmonious
omoi wa yozora wo koete
My love passes the stars
utsushidasu sore wa
to shine pure light
hikari no michishirube
back on our path
kanashii ketsui wa
I hope the rain will soothe
ame ga naderu darou
the pain of my sad decisions
yurushiau tsuyosa oshiete hoshii
Tell me how to be strong enough to forgive
douka aisuru koto wasurenaide
Please don't forget how to love